Like say welcome brothers and sisters to
another Wednesday question and answer
where we open up with the ten
commandments that God commanded for the
whole world to keep. Brother James.
>> Yes sir. And God spake all these words
saying I am the Lord thy God which have
brought thee out of the land of Egypt
out of the house of bondage. Thou shalt
have no other gods before me. Thou shalt
not make unto thee any graven image, or
any likeness of anything that is in
heaven above, or that is in the earth
beneath, or that is in the water under
the earth. Thou shalt not bow down
thyself to them, nor serve them. For I,
the Lord thy God, am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain, for the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day to
keep it holy. Sixth day shalt thou labor
and do all thy work, but the seventh day
is the Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In
it thou shalt not do any work, thou nor
thy son, nor thy daughter, thy man's
servant, nor thy maid servant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the sea, and all that
in them is, and rested the seventh day.
Wherefore the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and hollowed it. Honor thy father
and thy mother, that thy days may be
long upon the land, which the Lord thy
God giveth thee. Thou shalt not kill.
Thou shalt not commit adultery. Thou
shalt not steal. Thou shalt not bear
false witness against thy neighbor. Thou
shalt not covet thy neighbor's house.
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's
wife, nor his man's servant, nor his
maid servant, nor his ox, nor his ass,
nor anything that is thy neighbors. I
read Exodus 20:es 1- uh 17. May the Lord
add a blessing to the reading of this
word. In Jesus name we pray. Amen.
>> Amen.
So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague as well as
the long scripture questions and
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate. We are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So, please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Keep in
mind that this is a live stream, so feel
free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We're just
asking that you keep your questions to a
two scripture maximum. Let me introduce
to you the family that's on the panel
this evening. We got brother Dre. Good
evening,
>> brother Jerome.
>> Rest in peace.
>> Brother Julius.
>> Hey, good evening everybody.
>> Brother James,
>> good evening everyone.
>> Sister Deborah,
>> good evening.
>> Brother Sean,
>> And we have the guest caller with us.
And I'm brother Cornell. Sister Deborah,
what is our first question of the
program?
>> Yes. Uh there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A.
>> Uh at Yes. So Adam would like you to
explain Matthew 2
17 and 18.
>> All right. So we're going to ask brother
Julius to shed some light on that.
Matthew 2 vers 17 and 18.
>> Let's go there. James
and let's shed some light on this right
here. But what we going to do, we're
going to pick it up at verse 16 because
this is when in the days of Herod uh he
was trying to kill Jesus and he went and
slew all the children
uh two years old and under trying to
kill Jesus. But it was also the
fulfillment of a prophecy. Pick it up at
verse 16. Matthew 2 and 16. Brother
James, when you get it, go ahead, my
brother.
>> Then Herod, when he saw that he was
mocked of the wise men, was exceeding
wroth, and sent forth and slew all the
children that were in Bethlehem, and in
all the coast thereof, from 2 years old
and under, according to the time, which
he had diligently inquired of the wise
men.
>> So that was two years earlier. He tried
to kill Jesus and the wise men told him,
"Hey, he going to be born in Bethlehem."
Well, he was looking for him, didn't
find, he got mad. And so, continue verse
7 17. Then was fulfilled that which was
spoken by Jeremy the prophet saying,
"And Rama was there a voice heard,
lamentation, and weeping and great
mourning. Rachel weeping for her
children and would not be comforted
because they are not
>> because they in this case in this
context they were executed. They were
killed. Let's go to Jeremiah the 31st
chapter and look at the prophecy.
Two great baby killers in the Bible in
the days of Moses
and in the days of Jesus. when you get
it. Let's look at the uh the prophecy.
Jeremiah 31 and 15, my brother.
>> Thus sayeth the Lord, a verse was a
voice was heard and Rama
>> lament Rama
>> Rama is a territory that belonged to
Benjamin. Go ahead.
>> Lamentation and bitter weeping.
>> Yes.
>> Ra Rail weeping for her children
refusing.
>> Still Rachel. It's still Rachel. The New
Testament calls her Rachel, but it's the
same person. Go ahead.
>> Rail reaping for her children refused to
be comforted for her children because
they were not.
>> Wow. So therefore, why were they not?
Because they will be executed by Herod
the Great. So that's what that whole
scripture is about in Matthew the 2
chapter. Herod the Great killing all the
children, the the male babies two years
and older under trying to find Jesus.
And he just killed they called the
history calls it the slaughter of the
innocents.
>> Yeah.
>> So that's what that's all about.
>> Yeah. All right. We thank you for that
light there, brother. And uh we hope
that that answered their question as we
continue to move on. Moving on, Atica
Masala asks, "What's the deeper
significance about the Lord not allowing
Magdalene
not to be touched,
not to touch him upon his resurrection,
yet a few days later allow Thomas to do
so."
>> All right. So the significance brother
Jerome of Magdalene hey not being able
to touch Jesus and then a few days later
he allowed Thomas please shed some
light.
Well he had to be accepted of the father
first. But let's go read the verse where
he said don't touch him. Let's go to uh
St. John chapter 20
and pick it up at verse 15. Read it to
the 17.
Okay. John 20 verse 15-17
says, "Jesus saith unto her,"Woman, why
weepest thou? Whom seekest thou? She
supposing him to be the gardener, saith
unto him, Sir, if thou have borne him
hence, tell me where thou hast laid him,
and I will take him away." Jesus saith
unto her, "Mary." She turned herself and
saith unto him, Rabona, which is to say,
Master.
Jesus saith unto her, "Touch me not, for
I am not yet ascended to my father, but
go to my brethren, and say unto them, I
ascend unto my father and your father,
and to my God and your God."
And so um right after Jesus had
resurrected um from the dead, he he had
to go back to heaven and be accepted of
the father as the first fruits
of those that slept.
Okay? And we going to read that verse
too. You talking about those that going
to be resurrected from the dead. Jesus
is the first fruit where he had to be
accepted of the father. Okay? So let's
go on to 1 Corinthians chapter 15
and we're going to read one verse verse
20 and then we're going to go to
Leviticus 23 after that brother James
>> okay
>> 1 Corinthians 15 verse 20
>> it says but now is Christ risen from the
dead and become the first fruits of them
that slept
>> yeah so he got to be accepted of the
fathers so let's go to Leviticus 23
and read verse 10-2.
>> Okay,
>> these are is talking about one of the
feasts that we have to keep every year.
And what you going to read in here is
really pointing to the Lord Jesus who is
the first fruit in the verses we're
about to read. So Leviticus 23 verse
10-2.
Okay.
>> It says, "Speak unto the children of
Israel, and say unto them, when ye be
come into the land which I give unto
you, and shall reap the harvest thereof,
then ye shall bring a sheath of the
first fruits of your harvest unto the
priest."
And he shall wave the sheep before the
Lord to be accepted for you. On the
moral after the Sabbath, the priest
shall wave it. And ye shall ye shall
offer that day when ye wave the sheath
and he lamb without blemish of the first
year for a burnt offering unto the Lord.
>> Yeah. So Jesus is their first fruit. He
also is that he lamb that without that's
without blemish. That's that's talking
about Jesus. Okay. And so, uh, he the
first fruit of this harvest. And the
harvest is talking about the is really
the resurrection.
That's what it's talking about. That's
the harvest, you know. It's going to be
a first resurrection and a second
resurrection. Well, he the first fruit
of all of that. Okay. And so, uh, he
couldn't be touched. He had to be clean,
you know, and he couldn't take the risk
cuz who knows, Mary Magdalene could have
had some uncleanness upon him.
You know, the Lord said, "Touch me not."
So, just to be on the safe side,
don't run the risk of being made unclean
by her if she happen to be unclean. It's
best that nobody partake in him. And it
actually say that in that uh Leviticus
23:2 where you ain't supposed to partake
of none of the uh harvest until the
first fruit is accepted, which is Jesus.
Okay. So, now let's go to St. John
chapter 20
>> and we going to read verse 19- 21. We
going to skip.
Okay. John 20
19 through 20 it says
the then the same day at evening being
the first day of the week when the doors
were shut where the disciples were
assembled for fear of the Jews came
Jesus and stood in the midst and said
unto them peace be unto you.
>> All right. So let me say this. So now at
this time now Jesus been accepted of the
father as the first fruit you know
everything was perfect. All right. So
then he when he came back to the earth
he went and visited his disciples. At
this point he can he can be touched now
cuz he had already been accepted. All
right. But before he was his accept
being accepted he couldn't be touched.
Okay. All right. So now he gonna allow
himself to be touched. Go ahead and
read.
>> And when he had so said, he showed unto
them his hands and his side. Then were
the disciples glad when they saw the
Lord.
>> Mhm. And skip down to verse 27. Read it
to the 29. That be it. Then said he to
Thomas, which reach hither thy finger,
and behold my hands, and reach hither
thy hand, and thrust it into my side,
and be not faithless, but believing.
>> And Thomas answered and said unto him,
"My Lord and my God."
>> Yes.
>> Jesus saith unto
>> That's it. That's it. That's it. That's
all I got on that.
>> All right. Yes, sir. Good scripture
there. I like how Jesus said, "Be not
faithless, but believe."
>> Yes.
>> And that is the job for all that follow
him in truth. All right. Thank you for
that, brother. Hope that answered that
question. As we move on to our next one,
>> next one. Malikica
Banks says, "In regards to 1 Corinthians
15 35-47,
my mother always speaks of being
cremated when is her time. Does it
matter if a person doesn't have a
traditional burial?"
>> No, it doesn't matter. that is uh up to
the choice of the family
because like the Lord say for dust thou
art and into dust thou shall return. So
um let's go to 1 Corinthians 15
and let's pick it up at that verse 35
being that she said this is what her
mother always referenced. Go ahead and
read that.
But some man But some man will say, "How
are the dead raised up?" And with what
body do they come?
Thou fool,
>> thou fool, that which seest is not
quickened, except it die. And that which
thou seest, thou seest not thy body that
shall be, but bear gra.
So, we're not going to read all of that
because that's not particularly talking
about cremation and whether or not you
do a traditional burial or not. But,
however, we do know that cremation is uh
something that's okay for you to do if
that's how you see best fit for your
family. Um for a lot of times people
have been doing traditional funerals and
come to find out that the price was too
much for them to bear and then creation
was a cremation was a um option for some
of the families. But let's go back into
the Old Testament. Let's go back into
1st Samuel the 31st chapter. 1st Samuel
31.
And when we get there, brother, I want
you to pick it up at that verse one and
then we'll just read down into the story
so we can get a feel for what's
happening here because this is when the
Philistines fought against Israel. So
1st Samuel 31 and1. Go ahead.
>> Now the Philistines fought against
Israel and the men of Israel fled from
before the Philistines and fell down
slain in Mount Gilboa.
>> Mhm. And the Philistines followed hard
upon Saul and upon his sons. And the
Philistines slew Jonathan and Abinad and
Melhua
Saul's sons.
>> So we know that Saul was the the king,
the first king of Israel here. And his
sons Jonathan, Benadab, and Melua. These
were all Saul's sons. What happened in
three? And the battle went sore against
Saul, and the archers hit him, and he
was sore wounded of the archers.
>> All right. So, let's skip down, brother,
and get to the point of that verse. Uh,
pick it up at verse 8 for me. Go ahead.
>> And it came to pass on the mar when the
Philistines came to strip the slain that
they found Saul and his three sons
fallen in Mount Gilboa. So they found
Saul and his three sons all dead. And
what did they do?
>> And they cut off his head and stripped
off his armor and sent into the land of
the Philistines round about to publish
it in the house of their idols and among
the people.
>> Go ahead.
>> And they put his armor in the house of
Ashsteros. And they fastened his body to
the wall of Belshad.
Now, let's see what it what Israel did
here. Go ahead.
>> And when the inhabitants of Jabash
Gilead heard of that which the
Philistines had done to Saul, all the
valiant men arose and went all night and
took the body of Saul and the bodies of
his sons from the wall of Belshan and
came to Jeabesh and burnt them there. So
we see that they took Saul and his three
sons and took their bodies and they
burned them there. And then what did
they do with the bones in that last
verse
>> and they took their bones and buried
them under a tree at Jabesh and fasted
seven days. So even after they had took
Saul and his three sons body and burned
them there, then they took the bones and
they returned them unto the ground under
a tree at Jbash and fasted seven days.
So yeah, it's within your right to do a
cremation. But if you do the cremation,
should also do what else the Lord said,
that for dust thou art, unto dust shall
thou return. So you should take the
ashes and return your loved ones to the
dirt as the Lord has said in Genesis.
And some cemeteries will take the body
for you after they cremate them. They
will return it to the ashes for you. But
not a good idea to bring it home because
your home will be always unclean. So do
what thus says the Lord and return the
ashes back to the ground like the Lord
commanded. That's all I got.
All right, we hope that that answered
your question as we continue to push on.
>> Yes, moving on. Be alert as why do
people who are true Israelites say
sukot, shabbah, and shalom? Were these
words spoken by anyone in the Bible? Are
these words Yiddish words that belongs
to Esau?
All right, brother Dre. They got a
little bit tied up into that question,
but what what do you say, Dre?
>> Yeah, let's go to uh Genesis
33. We're going to look at something
there because the word suko, what it
means is, and it'll tell you right here,
Genesis 33. And we're gonna just read
one verse, verse 17. When you get it, go
ahead, brother.
And Jacob journeyed to Suko and built
him a house and made booths for his
cattle. Therefore, the name of this
place is called Suko.
>> So that's what the name means. It means
booths
are places where they resided at at the
time. But it simply means booths. And in
terms of
uh true Israelites,
let's look at something. Let's go to
Acts the second chapter,
Acts 2,
and we're going to read uh pick it up at
at verse
one. Go ahead when you get there,
brother. Acts 2:1 says, "And when the
day of Pentecost was fully come, they
were all with one accord in one place."
>> "And suddenly there came a sound from
heaven as a of a rushing mighty wind,
and it filled all the house where they
were sitting."
>> Mhm.
>> And there appeared unto them cloven
tongues like as a fire, and it set upon
each of them. So now skip down to verse
six and let's get to it. Go ahead.
>> Now when this was noised abroad, the
multitude came together and were
confounded because that every man heard
them speak in his own language.
>> Now they heard them speak in their own
language. But back up, read verse 5.
Let's see who these were that were there
speaking in their own language. Go
ahead. And there were dwelling at
Jerusalem Jews, devout men, out of every
nation under heaven.
>> Out of every nation under heaven, and
they heard the word spoke in their own
language. Read verse 89. Go ahead,
brother.
>> And how hear we every man in our own
tongue, wherein we were born.
Parththeians and Mes and Elommites and
the dwellers in Mesopotamia and in Judea
and Capacia and Pontis and Asia. Okay,
that's good because they didn't all of
them did not say shalom, sukoot and
shabbat. Okay, because they were Jews,
devout man out of every nation. But more
importantly, the Lord said he would with
stammering lips and another tongue will
he speak to us. Now
>> that's right.
>> I want I want you to consider this also.
Let's go to Zephaniah 3 and verse 9
because the thing is we could we could
go in into the language thing, but it's
so much more to know.
But know this part too. Zephaniah 3,
read verse 9. Go ahead, brother.
>> For then will I turn to the people of
pure language, that they may all call
upon the name of the Lord to serve him
with one consent.
>> Now, this is in the future. When the
Lord comes, he is going to turn to the
people a pure language. If you ask seven
people from seven different places
the name of Jesus or whatever, they will
tell you six or seven different names.
I suggest we just read the book in the
language that we were born in. English
is good enough because this word was
given to us to understand in whatever
language we were in. That's all I got.
Are they Yiddish words, Dre?
>> Uh, the thing about Yiddish as it c as
it uh as it speaks about shalom, shalom
is spelled s h a o m. In Yiddish, it's
spelled s h o e l.
>> At the end of the day, just read the
word in the language you was born. And
all it means is peace.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Yes. Peace.
>> And Sabbath means Shabbat means Sabbath.
>> That's it.
>> Yep.
>> All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered your question. As we move on to
our next question,
>> uh, next one. Charity says in Matthew 28
verse1,
Mark 16:2,
Luke 24 verse 1, and John 20 verse 1,
all indicate Jesus had risen before
Sunday morning. If each day
begins at sundown,
how can we be sure if Jesus rose at the
end of the Sabbath or on Sunday eve?
>> All right. Well, shall it, you know, we
asked in the beginning that you keep
your scriptures to a two scripture
maximum, but however, we're going to
turn it over to the guest caller and
share some light from there.
Why don't you just read each other real
quick and move on?
>> Okay. Uh starting with the f Matthew 28
and1. Read that one first.
>> Okay. Matthew 28:1 says, "In the end of
the Sabbath, and it began to drawn to
dawn toward the first day of the week,
came Mary Magdalene and the other Mary
to see the supplica."
Mark 16 and two. Oh, did you want to
Okay, go ahead. Guess
>> look, when you go to Genesis the first
chapter, it tell you the evening and the
morning is the Sabbath is the first day
and the evening and the morning is the
second day. But you know that the day
starts in evening when it's dark. So at
the end of the Sabbath day, that mean
it's about to go into the first day of
the week while it was yet dark. And it
said that they went to the supper. It
didn't say Jesus was rising, did it?
>> No. No.
>> Read the next one.
>> Okay. The next one was Mark 16 and2.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. That says, "And very early in the
morning, the first day of the week, they
came unto the supplica at the rising of
the sun."
>> Okay. Early in the morning. It was still
the first day of the week, wasn't it?
>> Yep. Yes, sir.
>> And at the rising of the sun. But we
going to show you that wasn't
necessarily the case. Read the next one.
>> Luke 24 and1.
>> Okay. Luke 24 and1 says,
"Now upon the first day of the week,
very early in the morning, they came
unto the supplica bringing the spices
which they had prepared and certain
others with them.
Now, the first day of the week, that's
still that's outside of the seventh day.
That mean that uh Jesus had already uh
uh uh uh had already died, didn't it?
>> Mhm.
>> Let's go to 20 St. John 201. Now, this
going to clear it all up. 21.
>> Okay. John 20 and1 says, "The first day
of the week cometh Mary Magdalene early
when it was yet dark
unto the supplica."
>> Mhm.
>> Now when it was yet dark
that mean the sun hadn't risen, hadn't
it?
>> No. Correct. Wasn't daylight
to the suppler finish there?
>> Unto the supplica and seeing the stone
taken away from the supplica.
>> Go ahead, read the next one.
>> Then she runth and cometh to Simon Peter
and to the other disciple whom Jesus
loved, and said unto them, they have
taken away the Lord out of the supplica,
and we know not where they have laid
him.
So now when they got there the first day
of the week it was still dark but it was
still on the first day of the week
because the the the evening in the
morning is the first day. So now to let
you know when they got there he didn't
rise on Sunday cuz he was not there. It
was still dark.
But the whole thing is Peter said we
have a more sure word of prophecy.
And let's look at the sure word of
prophecy. They established when Jesus uh
uh uh uh died and died and rose. Go into
Daniel's the 9th chapter and read verse
27.
>> Daniel 9 and 27 says, "And he shall
confirm the covenant with many for one
week. And in the midst of
>> Mhm.
>> this he that's confirmed the covenant
with many for one week is talking about
Jesus the Messiah." Okay. He shall
confirm the cover with for one week. Go
ahead.
>> And in the midst of the week, he shall
cause the sacrifice and the oblation to
cease.
>> Now, and that's what he did when Jesus
died on the cross. The veil of the
temple ripped and that ended animal
sacrifice.
But then he said in the midst of the
week, didn't it? What is the middle of
the week?
>> Wednesday.
>> All day long. Now, let's go into Matthew
the 12th chapter and find out how long
that Jesus, you know, how long Jesus was
going to be in the grave. Matthew's 12,
read verse 38 to 40.
>> Okay. Matthews 12 38-4 says, "Then
certain of the scribes and of the
Pharisees answered, saying, Master, we
would see a sign from thee."
But he answered and said unto them, "An
evil and adulterous generation seeketh
after a sign,
and there shall be and there shall be no
sign and there shall no sign be given to
it, but the sign of the prophet Jonas."
For as Jonas was three days and three
nights in the whale's belly, so shall
the Son of Man be three days and three
nights in the heart of the earth.
Now, so Jesus letting you know how many
days and nights he going to be there. So
he split one day cuz he come with the
evening and the morning. The evening is
the night and the morning is the
daytime. So he died in the middle of the
week. That mean he died on Wednesday,
right?
>> Yes.
>> So now that mean they put him in the
grave that Wednesday night. actually was
the beginning of Thursday, but we going
we going to keep it uh uh uh American
Gentile.
So they put him in the grave Wednesday
night, right?
>> So if he got three nights, he was in
there Wednesday night, Thursday night,
and Friday night. Okay. He said three
days. Okay. So it'll be Thursday in the
daytime, Friday in the daytime, and
Saturday in the daytime. and he rose
Saturday evening before
it was dark because it said three days
and three nights. That let you know that
Saturday is the Sabbath day with uh and
let you know that he rose on the Sabbath
day just before dawn. He couldn't go
into uh Sunday which was the first day
of the week started the first day of the
week because it then would have been
four nights. The prophecy lets you know
that he died and he was in the grave
Wednesday night, Thursday night, and
Friday night. And he's in there
Thursday, Friday, and Saturday. And he
rose Saturday just before sundown. So
that is that confirms that Jesus rose on
the Sabbath day. That's why when the
people got there the first day of the
week,
he was gone.
>> He was gone.
He rose before the sun went down on the
first day of the week. And when they got
there, it was dark. He was gone. So
there's an absolute absolute
confirmation that Jesus died on the
Sabbath day, which is called Saturday.
>> Yep.
Yep. It's correct. Cuz that dog brought
in a new day and it couldn't have been
that day.
>> That's correct.
He rose on the Sabbath day. Yes, sir.
>> All right.
We hope that answered your question
there as we continue to move to our next
one.
>> Next question. Cool Blue says, "I have a
friend that can't get past a past
relationship.
Can you please give them some scriptures
that will hopefully help alleviate their
pain?
All right, brother Julius, can you um
provide some scripts that will be of
help?
>> Who blue? Um look like I'm we're going
to help you out with some scripture, but
you have to be the one to apply it
because we don't know the past
relationship that this person that
you're referring to. We don't know the
conditions. We don't know their
relationship with God, but you do. So
now the first thing uh when I'm going
through or or hurt whatever it is that
the person went through evidently
there's some uh heavy pain but we don't
know what all the details are. So I
would give you a uh what's called a
generic answer but yet it's scripture.
Let's go to Psalm 107 James
>> because in this flesh and blood we're
going to experience ups and downs and
hurts and pains just like sometime we
experience some happy moments. But when
you're in a relationship you got to be
very careful to get past it because if
you don't you can seek into depression
and that's that's a rabbit hole you
don't want to go down into. the word of
God. Psalm 107, James verse 21. And I
would tell them to meditate on the word
of God.
21. And then we're going to back up and
read 20. Go ahead.
>> Oh, that men would praise the Lord for
his goodness and for his wonderful works
to the children of men.
>> Why? Verse 20.
>> He sent his word
them and healed them.
the word of God, sisters and brothers.
He sent this word in what, James?
>> And healed them.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And delivered them from their
destructions.
>> Let's back up to Psalm 34.
Psalm 34. Go and look at what David went
through and look how he prayed to the
Lord for forgiveness and for healing and
for comfort.
Psalm 34, just one verse 18, please.
The Lord is nigh unto them that are of a
broken heart.
>> Yes. And savest such as be of a contrite
spirit.
>> That's a humble spirit. My last
scripture, Psalm 30. Psalm 30.
And believe this and know this. Cool
blue. You could share this with that
person. You know him better than we do.
Psalm 30
verse 5 please.
>> For his anger endureth but a moment.
>> Yes.
>> And his favor is life.
>> Weeping may endure for a night.
>> But
>> but joy cometh in the morning.
>> That's all I got.
>> Seek ye the kingdom of God and seek ye
the king and his righteousness.
Establish a relationship with the Lord.
Read his word and you're going to run
into some comfort because you're not the
first and you're not the last. He sent
his word and it healed them. Yes, sir.
>> I said, can we read that verse two in
that same book?
>> Psalm Psalms 30
>> and verse two. Yep. In verse two,
>> it says, "Oh Lord my God, I have I cried
unto thee and thou hast healed me."
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Cry to the Lord.
>> That's right.
>> Suggest Kublu to this person that they
cry to the Lord.
have a repenting heart
and uh humble yourself and in due time
he'll lift you up.
>> Yeah, that's right. All right, we hope
that that provided some comfort for you,
Cool Blue, as we move on to our next
question.
>> Next question. Sky Rider would like you
to explain the parable of the five wise
virgins that had their all ready and
five foolish virgins who had none and
ask the five wise virgins for some.
>> All right. So we ask the guest caller,
can you shed some light on these 10
virgins? Five wise and five foolish.
Let's go to Matthew the 25th chapter
and going to read. We going to read
from 1 to3.
>> Okay.
Matthew 25:es 1 to13 says, "Then shall
the kingdom of heaven be likened unto 10
virgins which took their lamps and went
forth to meet the bridegroom."
and and five and five of them were wise
and five were foolish.
They that were foolish took their lamps
and took no oil with them.
>> But the wise took oil in their vessels
with their lamps.
While the bridegroom terried, they all
slumbered and slept. And at midnight
there was a cry made, "Behold, the
bridegroom cometh. Go ye out to meet
him.
>> Then all those virgins arose and trim
and trimmed their lamps.
>> And the foolish said unto the wise, Give
us your oil, for our lamps are gone out.
But the wise answered, saying, Not so,
least there be not enough for us and
you. But go ye rather to them that sell,
and buy for yourselves.
And while they were while they went to
buy, the bridegroom came, and they were
ready. And they that were ready went in
with him to the marriage, and the door
was shut.
>> Afterward came also the other virgin,
saying, Lord, Lord, open to us. But he
answered and said, "Verily I say unto
you, I know you not."
>> Watch therefore, for ye know neither the
day nor the hour wherein the son of man
cometh.
>> Okay? The oil that they have is a
righteousness of God.
That mean you have to be a servant of
God
all the time. You cannot take a break or
relief
like the unwise servant that started to
use the people. Then the Lord came the
time when he didn't look for him
and he cut him aside.
So the same thing is with you a servant
of God, you have to be a servant of God
continually.
Let's look at the uh 1 Thessalonians 5
and going we're going to read verses
1-8. 1 Thessalonians 5:es 1-8.
>> Okay. 1 Thessalonians 5 1-8 says, "But
of the times and the seasons, brethren,
ye have no need that I write unto you.
For yourselves know perfectly that the
day of the Lord so cometh as a thief in
the night.
>> Now talking about we talking about the
day of the Lord. It comes as a thief in
the night. That mean you have to be a
servant all time 24/7. Go ahead. For
when they shall say, "Peace and safety,"
then sudden destruction cometh upon
them, as travail upon a woman with
child, and they shall not escape.
>> Uhhuh. Go ahead.
>> But But ye, brethren, are not in
darkness, that that that day should
overtake you as a thief.
Ye are all the children of light and the
children of the day. We are not of the
night nor of darkness.
Therefore, let us not sleep as do
others, but let us watch and be sober.
>> Uhhuh.
>> For they that sleep sleep in the night,
and they that be drunken are drunken in
the night. But let us But let us who are
of the day be sober, putting on the
breastplate of faith and love, and for
in helmet the hope of salvation.
So in other words, you cannot start out
serving God and then get relaxed, go to
sleep spiritually, start doing things
like the unrighteous that the
unrighteous servants doing. God going
out, well, you know, uh uh I might
commit this sin, but I'm going to be
straight before the Lord come. You don't
know when the Lord's going to come. He
might even come for you through the
through death through the fif
wise word uh uh uh uh virgin was people
that serve God and they kept serving
God. The foolish version
stopped serving them. They went slack.
Not that they didn't know God because
they had oil, too. But what happened is
they ran out of gas just like you
running out of oil. Why is because their
patient went bad and they start breaking
God's laws
and they fell away and stopped being
what this this 8th verse said
that you are the children but let us who
are of the day be sober
putting on the breastplate of faith
and love and for and for a helmet the
hope of salvation. So long as you keep
that in your mind, you going to keep God
law, statute, and commandments. It's
obvious that the five
foolish version forgot. In other words,
they started this journey, but they
fainted before they ended it. That's all
I got to say.
>> Yep.
>> And that door got shut on them five
fools.
All right,
>> we're going to keep it moving to our
next question with a time check. Yes,
the time is 8:16.
Um, Jennifer Love has two questions. She
says, "Feast of the Lord in Leviticus 23
are holy. So, shouldn't our behavior be
as such and not doing our own pleasures,
TV, music, conversation, etc.
And isn't whatever our heart desires
refer to food and drinks.
>> All right. Indeed. That's a two-part
question. Brother Jerome, go right
ahead.
>> Um,
not doing our own pleasure. It's it's
not associated with every
um high Sabbath that that's mentioned in
Leviticus the 23rd chapter. So let's
let's take a look at them, you know,
because often times we look at all of
the feast days, even though they high
Sabbaths, we look at them like they
supposed to be kept like we keep the
weekly Sabbath and all of the high
Sabbaths in Leviticus the 23rd chapter
is not kept that way. Okay, so let's
look at a few of them. Okay, let's go to
uh Leviticus the 23rd chapter
>> and we're going to read verse 20 and 21.
Okay, Leviticus 23:es 20 and 21 says,
"And the priest shall wave them with the
bread of the first fruits for a wave
offering before the Lord with the two
lambs. They shall be holy to the Lord
for the priest.
>> And ye shall proclaim on the s selfs
same day that it may be in holy
convocation unto you. Ye shall do no
survile work therein. It shall be a
statue forever in all your dwellings
throughout your generations.
>> Now if you was to read a little bit
higher in there, it's talking about
Pentecost right there. Okay? It said
don't do no survival work, but on the
weekly Sabbath, it's no work at all. So,
it's it's a difference. Okay. And on the
um weekly Sabbath, it talk about, you
know, I think it's in Isaiah the 58th
chapter, you know, regarding your
pleasures, you know, don't do your own
pleasures on the Lord's Sabbath. Talking
about the weekly Sabbath, right? But
that's not a that's not applied here for
the uh Pentecost cuz it's talking about
no survile work. Okay? So if you happen
to say you wanted to uh cook you a
little something, it didn't say you
couldn't. All right. Um say you wanted
to watch you a recording program or
something. It didn't say you couldn't.
All right. It just said no survile work.
That's all it said right there. Okay.
Now, it's a feast nonetheless. So, we
know we going to be doing that. Now, are
we going to be rejoicing during that
feast? Of course, we are. But on the
weekly Sabbath, you ain't supposed to be
doing too much. You ain't supposed to be
doing your own pleasure. See, there's a
difference. All right. So, now let's go
to um Deuteronomy the 16th chapter and
let's read verse 9 through 11.
>> Okay. Deuteronomy 16:es 9-11.
>> Yeah, read it as quickly as you can.
>> Seven weeks shalt thou number unto thee.
Begin to number the seven weeks from
such time as thou beginest to put the
sickle to the corn.
>> Mhm. And thou shalt keep the feast of
weeks unto the Lord thy God, with a
tribute of a free will offering of thine
hand, which thou shalt give unto the
Lord thy God, according as the Lord thy
God hath blessed thee. And thou shalt
rejoice before the Lord thy God, thou
and thy son, and thy daughter, and thy
man's servant, and thy maid servant, and
the Levite that is within, thy gates,
and the stranger, and the fatherless,
and the widow that are among you, in the
place which the Lord thy God hath chosen
to place his name there."
>> Okay? And so, you know, let's just say
he he tell you to rejoice on that feast.
Okay? But, uh, it's still holy. So, it's
say it fall on the Sabbath. Say that
feast day fall on the weekly Sabbath.
All right? Now, you got to apply the
rules in regards to the weekly Sabbath.
All right?
you so you going stain from your own
pleasures then with the exception of
your rejoicing before the Lord and
keeping of the feast. You still
rejoicing but don't come at your husband
cuz it happened to fall on the weekly
Sabbath. See,
but let's say it fell on one of the
other days of the week. It's a little
different. Okay. So now um can you can
you go to
uh Leviticus
23 and read verse 24 and 25?
>> Leviticus 23 and verses 24 and 25
>> say speak unto the children of Israel
saying in the seventh month in the first
day of the month shall ye have a Sabbath
a memorial of blowing of trumpets and
holy convocation. Mhm.
>> Ye shall do no survile work therein, but
ye shall offer an offering made by fire
unto the Lord.
>> Once again, didn't say thou shall not do
any work. It said no survile work. Okay?
Now, that you know uh say that happened
to fall on a weekly Sabbath, then the
Sabbath day rules apply.
But let's say it didn't fall on a weekly
Sabbath. It fell on a Tuesday. Okay,
then that's different. Okay. Didn't say
you can't watch no TV. Didn't say you
couldn't kill no fire, you know, and
that's not a eating feast anyway. So,
but didn't say that. All right. So, um
that that's all I got. Anybody wanted to
add something?
>> What's it say on the day of atonement?
>> Yeah. And now on day of atonement it say
it it says it says
>> you want me to read 27 and 28 sir
[Music]
>> also on the 10th day of the seventh
month there shall be a day of atonement.
It shall be an holy convocation unto you
and ye shall afflict your souls and
offer an offering made by fire unto the
Lord.
And ye shall do no work in that same
day.
>> Yeah.
>> For it is a day of atonement to make an
atonement for you before the Lord your
God.
>> You know on that day instead of
rejoicing you supposed to flick yourself
and don't do any at all on that day.
>> Yeah.
>> So the Lord tell you what to do. We
don't need to add to it and assume.
That's all I have to say.
And uh sister Deborah, the last part of
that question, can you read that?
>> Yes. Um the second part of her question
is uh isn't whatever your heart desire
refer to food and drinks?
>> Yeah, there's a verse in uh I believe
it's Deuteronomy 14, is it? Or 16:14
that kind of deals with that. Let's go
read that right quick. Deuteronomy 14
verse 26.
And it'll let you know what it's dealing
with.
Okay. Deuteronomy 14 26 says, "And thou
shalt bestow that money for whatsoever
thy soul lusteth after, for oxen, or for
sheep,
>> that's food,
>> or for wine,
>> that's drink."
>> Or for strong drink.
>> Yeah. or for whatsoever thy soul
desireth, and thou shalt eat thereof
before the Lord thy God, and thou shalt
rejoice thou and thine household.
>> Yeah. And we also like to add within the
confines of the commandments of God. You
know, whatever your soul lusting about,
make sure it's within the confines of
the commandments. That's all I got.
>> Yeah. Okay. All right. I hope that
answered your question there as we move
on.
>> Moving on. Sandra Allen says, "I would
like to ask about feast of tabernacles.
Is the eighth day included in the three
times in a year all males appear before
the Lord and shall not appear empty?"
And do we give on the eighth day like
the first day? Like on the first day.
>> All right. So dealing with the feast
that have uh that is behind us now. We
have kept them all. Guest call them.
>> Let's go into Deuteronomy 16th chapter.
Read verses 16 and 17.
>> Okay.
Deuteronomy 16 16-1 17 says, "Three
times in a year shall all thy males
appear before the Lord thy God in the
place which he shall choose.
In the feast of unleaven bread, and in
the feast of weeks, and in the feast of
tabernacles,
and they shall not appear before the
Lord empty.
Every man shall give as he is able
according to the blessing of the Lord
thy God which he has given thee.
>> Now it didn't mention the eighth day
there but let's go into Leviticus the
23rd chapter and we're going to read
verse 36 first and then we're going to
skip.
>> Okay. Leviticus 23:36
says, "Seven days ye shall offer an
offering made by fire unto the Lord.
On the eighth day shall be in holy
convocation unto you,
and ye shall offer an offering made by
fire unto the Lord. It is a solemn
assembly, and ye shall do no survile
work therein."
Skip down and read verse 39.
Also in the 15th day of the seventh
month, when ye have gathered in the
fruit of the land, ye shall keep a feast
unto the Lord seven days.
On the first day shall be a Sabbath,
>> and on the eighth day shall be a
Sabbath. Sabbath.
>> Now that you know, if you uh in order
for you to keep a feast for the seventh
day, you have to bring some food.
In order to keep a feast on for the
eighth day and that is the feast day,
you have to bring some food and what and
about both of the Sabbath days. Read
that
>> and verse 40.
>> Verse 40. And ye shall take you on the
first day the bowls of godly trees,
branches of palm trees, and the bowls of
thick trees, and willows of the brook,
and ye shall rejoice before the Lord
your God seven days.
>> Finish it.
>> Oh, that was that was the end of verse
40, sir. And the reason that they said
you going to dwell in boots for seven
days because that's represent this
temporary dwelling. But either way it go
you feast for all eight days but only
seven of them represent the tabernacle
is because that represent flesh and
blood. Eight day represent spirit
beings. However, both of them are feast
day. So, in order for you to pull the
feast day, somebody have to do
something. It's not like now if you go
back and look at the scripture would
tell you that the uh donations and stuff
you made for the feast are supposed to
be separate from your yearly annual
donation during the years and your
tithes. You're supposed to get a special
tithe for the feast. So if you going to
eat and you will eat, you just won't eat
meat on this e day. Somebody have to
give something. That's all I have to
say.
>> All right. Well, hope that answered your
question there. As we continue to move
on, I believe Deborah, we're getting
ready to go into new territory.
>> Yes, we are. Uh we are now into
tonight's Q&A for Wednesday, October the
15th, 2025.
Philosophers says or philosophy says, I
was told there were two baptisms. I'm
confused on what the baptism of the Holy
Spirit is and how to refute that. I know
Mark 1 verse 8 is commonly used.
>> All right. And we're going to start
there that Mark 1 and8 and use it again
and then open it up to the panel.
>> Okay.
>> When you get there, brother,
>> when you get there, brother James, read
that and then the guest caller will shed
some light from there.
>> Okay. Mark 1 and verse8 says, "I indeed
have baptized you with water, but he
shall baptize you with the Holy Ghost."
>> Now you have to use understand the Holy
Ghost is nothing but slang for spirit
with the Holy Spirit.
>> Okay?
>> Yep.
>> And now let's go and see what happened,
what Peter said about baptism. Let's go
into Acts the second chapter cuz after
Peter told these people who they who
Jesus was and they understood that they
had crucified
the justice the just one then they had a
question. Acts 2 verse 37 and 38.
>> Okay. It says, "Now when they heard
this, they were pricricked in their
heart and said unto Peter and to the
rest of the apostles, men and brethren,
what shall we do?"
Then Peter said unto them, "Repent and
be baptized every one of you in the name
of Jesus Christ for the remission of
sins, and ye shall receive the gift of
the Holy Ghost." and you shall receive
the gift of the Holy Ghost. Now, let's
go and see if we can find out what that
is. Let's go into St. John the 6th
chapter.
We're going to read verses 51 to 54.
Then we going to skip.
>> Okay. John 6 verse uh 51-54 says, "I am
the living bread which came down from
heaven. If any man eat of this bread, he
shall live forever. And the bread that I
will give is my flesh, which I will give
for the life of the world.
The Jews therefore stro the Jews
therefore strove among themselves,
saying, How can this man give us his
flesh to eat?
Then Jesus said unto them, "Verily,
verily, I say unto you, except ye eat
the flesh of the Son of Man, and drink
his blood, ye have no life in you.
Whosoever eateth my flesh and drinkkeeth
my blood have eternal life, and I will
raise him up at the last day."
>> Okay, we know that Jesus not talking
about bite his flesh and eat his blood.
And and they said this is a hard saying.
What verse are you?
>> That was 54 sir.
>> Skip down to verse 60 and read it.
>> Many there.
>> Okay. 60 and 61 says, "Many therefore of
his disciples when they had heard this
said, this is an hard saying. Who can
hear it?" When Jesus knew in himself
that the disciples murmured at it, he
said unto them, "Doeth this offend you?"
>> Jip down to 63 and read it.
>> It is the spirit that quickenth.
The flesh profiteth nothing. The words
that I speak unto you, they are spirit
and they are life.
>> So he's not talking about consume his
flesh and blood. He telling you to
consume his word.
So now when that word come upon you,
that is a spiritual baptism. Skip down
and read verse 66 to 68.
>> Okay, it's it says
>> from that time many of his disciples
went back and walked no more with him.
Then said Jesus unto the twel, will ye
also go away? Then Simon Peter answered
him, "Lord, to whom shall we go, thou
has the words of eternal life?"
That is what will get you eternal life.
The word of the Lord. You hear it, that
mean it endes you and you live it. And
Jesus and when and and when and when
that happens, Jesus comes into you
and suck with you. Let's last place.
Let's go in Revelation the 20th chapter
uh the third chapter and read verse 20.
>> Okay.
Revelation 3 and verse 20 says, "Behold,
I stand at the door and knock. If any
man hear my voice and open the door, I
will come in to him and will s with him
and he with me.
So that's the door of your mind. He
knocking. I can say in the psalm, the
day that you hear the word of God,
harden not your heart. So he will come
into you if you open your mind. That's
when you start your spiritual baptism.
Because if you continue in that word,
you will get eternal life.
>> So now,
>> yes,
>> man can only baptize you with water. But
the Lord is the one going to baptize you
with his word because he going to give
you increase in the mind and understand
it. So when it said he going to baptize
you with the Holy Ghost, doesn't me
merely mean that he going to baptize you
with his word. He going to open your
mind and let you understand what you
need to do to get eternal life. That's
all it means.
>> Praise the Lord is a blessing in itself.
>> All right, we hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Shanquila Au jobi says in
Matthew 28
13 and vers and verse 15 chief priests
bribe Roman guards to spare a false
story about Jesus resurrection.
Could this suggest how other religions
like Hinduism, Islam, Buddhism, and
Catholicism began?
>> All right, let's go to the book is
Matthew 28, right? Deborah 13 and 15.
>> Yes.
>> All right, let's read that, James. And
let's open that up also to the panel.
>> Okay. Matthew 28:13 says, "Saying say
ye, his disciples came by night and
stole him away while he was sleep while
while we sleep slept."
Verse 15 says, "So they took the money
and did as they were taught." And this
saying is commonly reported among the
Jews until this day.
>> All right. And and that question again
as we open it up to the panel.
>> Yes. They uh he asked could this suggest
he says could this suggest how other
religions
began
about this false story about Jesus
resurrection?
>> No, that don't suggest that.
>> No, it does not.
It suggest exactly what it says
that
Pharisees bribed the soldiers to tell a
lie.
>> Yep. Big lie.
>> And these other religions always had
their pagan gods.
>> Even before Jesus came on the scene.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Let's think about it. Who is who is
Baal? Wasn't Baal before Jesus? Yep.
>> Then you got Rim
before
>> Asteroth.
>> Uhhuh.
>> All them gods. So the other ones may
have been uh uh uh extracts from those
pagan worshippers, but they was way it
was around way before Jesus. So that No,
you can't suggest that.
>> Okay. Hope that answered your question.
Next one.
Next one. Malikica Banks asks you to
clarify
the time the Sabbath begins every week.
She states, "I always thought it was at
sundown."
>> No, it's not sundown. When the sun go
down, the west is still lit up. It's
still very bright over there. It's when
it's dark out that you have began the
Sabbath on Friday night. What was that
scripture, brother Dre, that we were
talking about on the panel?
>> Proverbs 7 and9.
>> Let's go there. Proverbs 7 and9.
This will bring in your Sabbath day
right here.
If you like, Drake, feel free. Go ahead.
Proverbs 7:9 says, "In the twilight, in
the evening, in the black and dark
night."
That's when the day starts at evening in
the black and dark night. That means
that it has to be nighttime all the way
around, east and west.
>> That's correct. And and also you have a
lot of people that soon as the sun go
down, even though it's still bright over
there, you got everyone saying happy
Sabbath, happy Sabbath. No, not yet.
When it's according to this Proverbs 7
and verse 9, when it's dark, even on the
west, when you look west, it should be
dark across there. Now, we are bringing
in the Sabbath because the sun rises in
the east and sets in the west. So, it
must be dark over there.
All right, we hope that answered your
question as we move on.
>> Moving on. JR asks, "Are there any
scriptures that support Paul is talking
to believers in Colossians 2 verse 16?"
>> Let's go to Colossians 2, James.
Colossians 2
and let's pick it up at that verse
16.
>> Okay, hold on one second for me. Just
getting there. Colossians 2 and 16.
>> It says, "Let no man therefore judge you
in meat or in drink or in respect of an
holy day or of the new moon or of the
Sabbath days.
And they want to know if what Deborah
>> does this scripture support Paul is
talking to believers.
>> Open to the fact
>> in respect of in respect of read that
again brother Jack. It says, "Let no man
therefore judge you in meat or in drink
or in respect of an holy day or of the
new moon or of the Sabbath days."
>> Keep reading.
>> Which are a shadow of things to come,
but the body is of Christ.
>> Go ahead. Let no man begal you of your
reward in a voluntary humility and
worshiping of angels intruding into
those things which he have not seen
verely puffed up by his fleshly mind
>> they never go that go and read about
that where they said intrude in you know
with angels you understand what I'm
saying
>> correct these Colossians are Gentiles
these are not talking about the Lord's
holy days
cuz Paul told you that Gentiles
sacrifice to devils. He's talking about
they high Sabbath day like Christmas and
Easter and all that kind of stuff. Y'all
understand?
>> Yeah.
>> But the Gentiles know about God's high
days. Even today, how many Gentiles keep
the day of Pentecost?
>> Very few.
>> How many Gentiles uh uh keep the Lord's
Sabbath days?
Mhm.
>> Not many.
>> Not many keep the atonement.
>> Think about it. So he's talking telling
them about they days. Somebody assumed
that he was talking about it. No.
Gentiles didn't know nothing about uh uh
uh uh uh God's days.
He was talking about and one of them
they they never rent. and being and also
uh uh uh uh uh what is what does it say
about angels
and worshiping of angels? Is this what
it said?
>> Yeah. Let no man begal you of your
reward in a voluntary humility and
worshiping of angels.
>> Yep.
>> What is Satan?
>> An angel.
>> Angel
>> a follower.
And will somebody go and read what Paul
said who the Gentiles
sacrifice to.
>> All right, we're in search mode. Be up
with that shortly.
>> 1 Corinthians 10
and 20.
>> Okay. 1 Corinthians 10 and 20 says, "But
I say that the things which the Gentiles
sacrifice, they sacrifice to devils and
not to God. And I would not that ye
should have fellowship with devils."
>> Now, to let you know that he was talking
about that,
what did Paul do about the feast? I
think it's a a Sabbath day. What is in
in uh uh acts
uh where you reason in the synagogues
and also you had to keep the feast. Acts
18 first I think.
>> Yeah, I think it's Act 18 and4.
Acts 18 and4.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. was
>> Acts 18 and4 says, "And he reasoned in
the synagogue every Sabbath and
persuaded the Jews and the Greeks."
>> Now, how can he tell you not to uh be
judged on the Sabbath? And he doing it.
Now, further on this 18th chapter, for
his uh feast in Jerusalem and his 18th
uh uh uh uh 8
>> uh
>> chapter,
>> 19
>> verse 21 1821.
Okay, read it.
>> You said 18 and 21. No.
>> Yeah. 18 to 20 and 21. Yeah.
>> Okay. It says, "But bathe them farewell,
saying, I must by all means keep this
feast that
>> back up a little bit. Let I want you to
let where he was. He was in Ephesus."
>> Okay.
>> 19.
>> Verse 19. And he came to Ephesus and
left them there.
But he himself entered into the
synagogue and reasoned with the Jews.
When they desired him to tarry longer
time with them, he consented not, but
bade them farewell, saying, "I must by
all means keep this feast that cometh in
Jerusalem, but I will return Mhm.
>> finish it.
>> But I will return again unto you if God
will." and he sailed from Ephesus.
>> Now, how is it that Paul gonna keep this
keep the feast
and tell them not to do it? The
Colossians, go to the 20th chapter
of Acts
and you see what he said about
Pentecost. But that time he left Ephesus
early because he wanted to keep the
feast that go on in Jerusalem. This time
he bypassed them.
>> Acts 20
>> verse 16.
>> What's it say?
>> Yeah.
>> For Paul had determined to sell by
Ephesus because he would not spend the
time in Asia. For he had hasted if it
were possible for him to be at Jerusalem
the day of Pentecost.
>> So how is that Paul going to tell you
not to do something? Don't be judged in
it. And he is doing it
>> right.
>> We got the say he reason that Jews and
the Greeks. He kept the feast that cover
all of them. Then he kept Pentecost
which is another feast. Now you going to
tell me I can't keep them. No. Paul was
talking to the Colossians and he was
talking to them about their holy days
>> and their Sabbath.
>> Don't the people that call themselves
Christians says Sunday is the Christian
Sabbath day?
>> Right. Yes, they do.
>> Don't they say Christ was born on the
25th day of December?
>> Yes, they do.
>> They died Good Friday and rose a Sunday
morning.
>> Yes.
>> Yep.
>> All three of those I just stated are
lies.
But they come from the Gentiles and and
what did Paul say? They get the they
they worship paperh
sacrifice of the devils.
>> Give you another example. The beast that
have seven heads and 10 horns which
represent you.
Where did he get his power from?
>> The dragon.
>> Dragon.
>> Satan. The devil. Ain't that correct?
>> That's correct.
>> I was seeing great authority.
>> Uh-huh. And when and when Jesus getting
ready to born be born,
why don't we go and and and and let's go
and look at that right quick. Let's go
into Revelations uh 12th chapter.
>> Yes sir.
>> Start reading at verse one.
>> Okay. Revelation 12 and1 says, "And
there appeared a great wonder in heaven,
a woman clothed with the sun and the
moon under her feet, and upon her head a
crown of 12 stars."
>> Uhhuh. And she being with child cried,
travailing in birth, and pain to be
delivered.
Go ahead.
>> And there appeared another wonder in
heaven. And behold, a great red dragon,
having seven heads, and 10 horns, and
seven crowns upon his heads.
And his tail drew the third part of the
stars of heaven.
And it cast him to the earth. And the
dragon stood before the woman which was
ready to be delivered for to devour her
child as soon as it was born.
>> Now, who is that dragon?
>> The devil.
>> But Satan is a cherub angel. And what's
a cherub angel look like according to
the scripture?
>> Four faces.
>> Six wings,
>> half feet,
>> eyes all over the body.
>> Uhhuh. He didn't look. So why is it that
he looked like uh uh seven heads and 10
horns that stood before the woman? It's
because he is ruling these gentile
nations
>> because and Paul called it they do
sacrifice to devils.
And so all those days in Colossians this
Paul said don't be judged then was
talking about the Gentiles holy days not
Israel. That's all I got to say.
>> Yep. That's true. And we didn't read it,
but I know in that Colossians 2, uh,
Paul was even warning them in verse 8.
He said, "Beware lest any man spoil you
through philosophy and vain deceit,
after the tradition of men, after the
rudiments of the world, and not after
Christ."
>> Yes, sir.
>> That's it. That tells it all. It got
nothing to do with the laws of God. He
tell you stay away from them uh holy
days that Satan set up among the
Gentiles.
>> Yep. All right. Was some good light we
shed there. We hope that answered your
question as we move on with a time
check.
>> Yes, the time is 8:52.
Uh Christy Watson asks in Leviticus 23
verse41. We're on these feast days,
>> feast of tabernacle.
>> Why is it that we don't observe the
feast for seven days? Scripture says it
shall be a statue forever.
>> All right, let's go and read that and
then we'll ask the guest caller to open
some light on that. Leviticus 23 and
let's pick it up at that verse 41. She
want to know why is it that the feast is
not kept for seven days. Go ahead,
brother.
>> Yes.
>> And ye shall keep it a feast unto the
Lord seven days in the year. It shall be
a statue forever in your generations. Ye
shall celebrate it in the seventh month.
>> That's called ahead.
>> Ye shall dwell in booth seven days. All
that are Israelites born shall dwell in
booths
that your gener
show you
how many times you supposed to have a
holy convocation.
Skip down to that would be 44
>> 39
>> we just read
>> verse 39
>> 39
>> also in the 15th day of the seventh
month when ye have gathered in the fruit
of the land ye shall keep a feast unto
the Lord seven days on the first day
shall be a Sabbath and on the eighth day
shall be a Sabbath.
>> Okay. And you got another scripture that
says that you shall have a holy
convocation
on what days?
Hey, search mode for that.
>> Still searching.
>> Yeah. Verse 34.
>> Um, let's see.
>> Say that again, Julius.
>> Verse 34. tell you the 15th day of the
seven months shall be a feast of
tabernacles for seven days unto the
Lord. But he command you to have a holy
convocation on the first day.
>> Right?
>> And on the eighth day
>> and on the correct
>> Did you read verse 36?
>> 36. No. And 37. But 36 says, "Seven days
you shall offer an offering made by fire
unto the Lord. on the eighth day shall
be in holy convocation unto you, and ye
shall offer an offering made by fire
unto the Lord. It is a solemn assembly,
and ye shall do
>> no survile work therein.
>> Yeah. And verse 35 talks about the uh
the seven day, the first day of the
feast of tabernacle is in 35
>> holy convocation.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Read that 35, Jane. on 35 says,
"On the first day shall be in holy
convocation. Ye shall do no survile work
therein."
>> Okay.
>> Seven days.
>> Oh.
>> Mhm.
>> Holy convocation you shall have on the
first day and on the
>> eighth day and on the eighth day. On the
eighth day. What's convocation?
A holy gathering. Gather. get together
>> gathering. Go to uh uh Leviticus 23 and
verse read verse three.
>> Okay. Leviticus 23 and verse three says,
"Six days shall work be done, but the
seventh day is the Sabbath of rest and
holy convocation. Ye shall do no work
therein. It is the Sabbath of the Lord
in all your dwellings."
So holy convocation mean you come
together.
>> Now you can feast the whole seven days
but it's probably everybody in their
family wherever they doing
>> just like taking a week of vacation. But
to come together as a whole but to have
a holy congregation that mean the whole
nation got to come together then in one
place.
>> Yeah. Now if you feast in one in the
same place for seven days or eight days
now you having a holy convocation for
eight days
>> right
>> now you violating
>> for you to do it for two the first and
the eighth. So that's why we only do it
because those are only two days that the
Lord said have a holy convocation that's
a holy gathering
>> first day.
>> Yeah. But you going to feast all seven
days, but you ain't going to have a holy
convocation but on the first day and on
the eighth day.
>> You can be feast at your own house.
>> Yeah, that's right. That's right. Yeah.
>> Yeah. And Lord saying you shall proclaim
all of these in their seasons.
>> That's it.
>> So that's why we only have two days
because if you if we come together and
feast seven days, the whole congregation
now we are violating the word of God. If
he wanted us to do seven, he said he
would have said, "And you shall have a
holy convocation for eight days."
>> Yep.
>> Yeah.
>> Didn't say that, did he?
>> Nope. First day, eighth day.
>> Yeah.
>> Y
[Music]
>> Yes, indeed. We rest our case. And that
was some more good light right there.
Next question, Deborah, as we are down
to our last question or two.
>> Uh, yes. Uh, Red Wolf says, "I grew up
with some native Indians tradition
wearing skins with fringes. I know the
law is written in my mind. I never wore
fringes for that purpose. Should I not
wear them or so not to appear
unrighteous?"
>> All right. Open to the panel dealing
with those fringes. just calling. What
do the fringes have to do with
righteousness?
>> Let's go.
Where is it? Where where the Lord where
the man Lord had a man stone and death.
>> Numbers 15.
>> Okay. See, they talk fringes, but they
don't know. Don't ever use what the
reason that you put on the fringes.
>> Exactly.
>> So, why don't you go to numbers? What
you say? Start at 15.
>> Yeah. 15. and pick it up around that 32
if you want to pick it up where the man
got stone gathering sticks.
>> Okay,
>> there you go. That's what we don't want
to know. See, if you going to wear
something, you got to have a reason to
wear if God tell you to do it.
>> Okay. Numbers 15 and verse 32 says, "And
while the children of Israel were in the
wilderness, they found a man that
gathered sticks upon the Sabbath day.
And they that found him gathering sticks
brought him unto Moses and Aaron and
unto all the congregation.
And they put him inward because it was
not declared what shall be done to him."
And the Lord said unto Moses, "The man
shall be surely put to death. All the
congregation shall stone him with stones
without the camp."
>> So that was that was talking about
breaking the law then, right?
>> Correct.
>> And all the congregation brought him
without the camp and stoned him with
stones, and he died as the Lord
commanded Moses.
And the Lord spake And the Lord spake
unto Moses, saying, "Speak unto the
children of Israel, and bid them that
they make them fringes in the borders of
their garments throughout their
generations."
>> Oh, yeah.
>> And that they put upon the fringe of the
borders a ribbon of blue.
>> Go ahead.
>> And it shall be unto you for a fringe,
that ye may look upon it.
and remember all the commandments of the
Lord and do them.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And that ye seek not after your own
heart and your own eyes after which ye
use to go aid.
>> Yes.
>> So now why did you put these strangers
to to remind you to keep the law? Isn't
that correct?
>> Correct.
>> But it didn't work. Go to Hebrews the
8th chapter. Start around verse 7.
>> Okay.
Hebrews 8,
Hebrews 8 and verse 7 says, "For if that
first covenant had been faultless, then
should no place have been sought for the
second."
>> Uhhuh. For finding fault with them, he
saith, "Behold, the days come, sayaeth
the Lord, when I will make a new
covenant with the house of Israel and
with the house of Judah."
>> Go ahead.
>> Not according to the covenant that I
made with their fathers in the day when
I took them by the hand to lead them out
of the land of Egypt, because they
continued not in my covenant, and I
regarded them not, sayeth the Lord.
Go ahead.
>> For this is the covenant that I will
make with the house of Israel after
those days, sayaeth the Lord. I will put
my laws in their mind, and write them in
their hearts, and I will be be to them a
god, and they shall be to me a people.
>> Now listen, is God a vain God?
>> No.
If if he gave you fringes to remind you
to keep them uh uh uh laws, why would he
give you uh uh why would he put his laws
now in with your inward part? Because
like he said, you disre you broke his
covenant. They kept saying it. Then he
added animal sacrifice
to keep from killing them all. But that
didn't work. So he made a new covenant.
Now the law is in your mind.
>> Yeah. And you don't have no need for
fringes cuz it didn't work in the first
place. That old saying about the fringes
is uh our culture. That's the biggest
lie ever been told. If it was our
culture, we would have had them on when
we come out of Egypt.
>> That's all I got to say.
>> Yeah. So, in regards to your question,
you do not need to wear your fringes.
Has nothing to do with righteousness,
obeying God, because he put it in our
laws and in our inward parts. And if you
just have to wear them, you should get
you a few cows and sacrifice them, too.
So, they was under the same covenant.
>> Old covenant.
>> Yeah.
>> All right, Sister Deborah. Time check.
>> The time is 9:03.
>> 9:03. Well, we hope that that answers
your question as we continue to say
thank you once again from all around the
world who tuned in with us and sending
in your questions. If you send in a
question and we didn't have a chance to
answer it, please don't resubmit. Sister
Deborah, take it, put it in rotation,
and we will address that question next
week. So, until we all come together
again, be safe, be blessed, stay prayed
up, and may the Lord have mercy on us
all as brother James closes us out. Our
Father, which art in heaven, hallowed be
thy name. Thy kingdom come, thy will be
done in earth as it is in heaven. Give
us this day our daily bread, and forgive
us our debts as we forgive our debtors,
and lead us not into temptation, but
deliver us from evil. For thine is the
kingdom and the power and the glory
forever. In Jesus name we pray. Amen.
Amen.